Guide to the Kenneth Reichard Photograph Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Kenneth Reichard photograph collection
1946-1952
PC0018
Reichard, Kenneth.
1.75 Linear feet (685 photoprints)
35 photonegatives: glass.
14 photonegatives: nitrate.
812 photonegatives: safety.
Scenes of Stanford University campus life commissioned by the University for publicity and development, and for publication in the Stanford Alumni Review and other Stanford publications.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professional photographer.
Description of the Collection
Scenes of Stanford University campus life commissioned by the University for publicity and development, and for publication in the Stanford Alumni Review and other Stanford publications.
Access Terms
Reichard, Kenneth.; Stanford University. News and Publications Service; Big Game.; Photonegatives; Photoprints.; Student life.
Collection Contents
- Prints and negatives
  - Prints, miscellaneous: old clock tower, faculty housing area, and 5 enlargements from negative rolls, 1 (Box 1)
  - Prints from historic glass plate negatives: Stanford University Band, palm drive, earthquake damage in San Francisco, Wawona Hotel, 3 men on horseback, unidentified houses, 2 (Box 1)
  - Contact prints, rolls 1-14, 3 (Box 1)
  - Contact prints, roll 201, 4 (Box 1)
  - Contact prints, rolls 202, 283, 5 (Box 1)
  - Contact prints, rolls 309, 311, 6 (Box 1)
  - Contact prints, rolls 314, 334, 7 (Box 1)
  - Contact prints, roll 445, 8 (Box 1)
  - Contact prints, rolls CC, C30, 9 (Box 1)
  - Contact prints, rolls C48, EE, 10 (Box 1)
  - Contact prints, rolls S, W, 11 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Walt Peterson, 1956, 12 (Box 1)
  - Hammer and Coffin song lyrics, ca. 1949, 13 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 14 (Box 1)
  - Negatives, rolls 1-14, 15 (Box 1)
  - Negatives, rolls 1-12; 201 (#24-83); 202, 16 (Box 1)
  - Negatives, rolls 283; 309 (#1-12 and 25-36), 17 (Box 1)
  - Negatives, rolls 311; 314; 334, 18 (Box 1)
  - Negatives, roll 445, 19 (Box 1)
  - Negatives, roll C-3 [35 mm film], 20 (Box 1)
  - Negatives, rolls C30; C48; CC, 21 (Box 1)
  - Negatives, rolls EE; S (#12-24); W, 22 (Box 1)
- 4x5" Safety negatives
  - Geology corner, 1 (Box 2)
  - Geology corner, 2 (Box 2)
  - Geology corner, 3 (Box 2)
  - Geology corner, 4 (Box 2)
  - Women on dorm steps, 5 (Box 2)
  - Women on dorm steps, 6 (Box 2)
  - Women in front of dorm, 7 (Box 2)
  - Women in front of dorm, 8 (Box 2)
  - Front of Wilbur Hall, 9 (Box 2)
  - Front of Wilbur Hall, 10 (Box 2)
  - Front of Wilbur Hall, 11 (Box 2)
  - Courtyard of Wilbur Hall, 12 (Box 2)
  - Courtyard of Wilbur Hall, 13 (Box 2)
  - Courtyard of Wilbur Hall, 14 (Box 2)
  - Front view of Quad with parked cars, 15 (Box 2)
  - Front view of Quad with parked cars, 16 (Box 2)
  - Front view of Quad with two people walking, 17 (Box 2)
  - Front view of Quad with two people walking, 18 (Box 2)
  - Students on History Corner steps, 19 (Box 2)
  - Students on History Corner steps, 20 (Box 2)
  - Students on History Corner steps, 21 (Box 2)
  - Students on History Corner steps, 22 (Box 2)
  - Front view of Quad (Law School building), 23? (Box 2)
  - Front view of Quad (Law School building), 24 (Box 2)
  - Students walking along side of Quad, 25 (Box 2)
  - Students walking along side of Quad, 26 (Box 2)
  - Students walking along side of Quad, 27 (Box 2)
  - Students walking along side of Quad, 28 (Box 2)
  - Students walking along side of Quad, some on bikes, 29 (Box 2)
  - Students along side of Quad, 30 (Box 2)
  - Campus street (The Row?), 31 (Box 2)
  - Campus street (The Row?), 32 (Box 2)
  - Campus street (The Row?), 33 (Box 2)
  - Street and house entrance (fraternity?), 34 (Box 2)
  - Street and house entrance (fraternity?), 35 (Box 2)
  - Street and house entrance (fraternity?), 36 (Box 2)
  - People on a terrace, 37 (Box 2)
  - People on a terrace, 38 (Box 2)
  - People on a terrace, 39 (Box 2)
  - Oblique view of Oval, Old Chem, Museum (from Hoover building?), 40 (Box 2)
  - Oblique view of Oval, Old Chem, Museum (from Hoover building?), 41 (Box 2)
  - Oblique view of Quad, 42 (Box 2)
  - Oblique view of Quad, 43 (Box 2)
  - Oblique view of Quad, 44 (Box 2)
  - Oblique view of Quad, 45 (Box 2)
  - Canoe on Lake Lagunita, 46 (Box 2)
  - Student at boat house rail looking over Lake Lagunita, 47 (Box 2)
  - Student at boat house rail looking over Lake Lagunita, 48 (Box 2)
  - Students at boat house deck, 49 (Box 2)
  - Students at boat house deck [some damage to negative], 50 (Box 2)
  - Negatives with duplicate numbers:
    - View of campus from Lathrop Hill, [10] (Box 2)
    - View of campus from Frenchman's Hill, [13] (Box 2)
    - View of campus from Frenchman's Hill, [14] (Box 2)
- 2.25 x 2.25" safety negatives
  - Hoover Tower (and Library steps) seen through arch, 15-16 (Box 3)
  - Engineering Corner (17) and possibly a close-up of tree bark (18), 17-18 (Box 3)
  - Cars on street with Hoover Tower in back, 19-20 (Box 3)
  - Frost Amphitheater?, 21-22 (Box 3)
  - People in Frost Amphitheater? (large expanse of lawn being watered and people playing with water), 23-24 (Box 3)
  - People in Frost Amphitheater?, 25-26 (Box 3)
  - Inner Quad views, 27-28 (Box 3)
  - View of Memorial Court through triple arch (29) and Front of Memorial Church (30), 29-30 (Box 3)
  - People in inner quad, triple arch in background (31) and View down arcade (32), 31-32 (Box 3)
  - View down arcades (blurry students), 33-34 (Box 3)
  - View along side of Quad (possibly from History Corner to Engineering Corner), 35-36 (Box 3)
  - Fountain in front of library (37) and East portal of Quad (38), 37-38 (Box 3)
  - Hoover Tower, 39-40 (Box 3)
  - Hoover Tower, 41-42 (Box 3)
  - Hoover Tower, 43-44 (Box 3)
  - Professor and students standing in Arch (Prof. Barclay?), 52-53 (Box 3)
  - Professor and students standing in Arch (Prof. Barclay?), 54-55 (Box 3)
  - Professor and students standing in Arch (Prof. Barclay?), 56-57 (Box 3)
  - Professor and students standing in Arch (Prof. Barclay?), 58-59 (Box 3)
  - Professor and students standing in Arch (Prof. Barclay?), 60-61 (Box 3)
  - Students on arcades (inner quad), 62-63 (Box 3)
  - Women in front of dorm [damaged negatives], 64-65 (Box 3)
  - Women in front of dorm [damaged negatives], 66-67 (Box 3)
  - Women in front of dorm [damaged negatives], 68-69 (Box 3)
  - Women in front of dorm [damaged negatives], 70-71 (Box 3)
  - Women in front of dorm [damaged negatives], 72-73 (Box 3)
  - Women in front of dorm (74) and bikes in front of dorm (75) [damaged negatives], 74-75 (Box 3)
  - Probable copy negatives (5): view of campus over Lake Lagunita, pre 1906 (Box 3)
  - Stanford Fund images 1-2, 40545 (Box 3)
  - Stanford Fund image 3, 3 (Box 3)
  - Stanford Fund image 4, 4 (Box 3)
  - Stanford Fund images 5-6, 40669 (Box 3)
  - Stanford Fund images 7-8, 40732 (Box 3)
  - Stanford Fund images 9-10, 40796 (Box 3)
  - Stanford Fund images 11-12, 40859 (Box 3)
  - Stanford Fund images 13-14, 13-14 (Box 3)
  - Stanford Fund images – contact prints, 40557 (Box 3)
  - Mechanical Engineering negs 1958 (professor in lab, some students), ME 1-12 (Box 3)
  - Mechanical Engineering negs 1958 (professor in front of class), ME 13-24 (Box 3)
  - Mechanical Engineering negs 1958 (professor in office), ME 25-36 (Box 3)
  - Mechanical Engineering negs 1958 (lab and class scenes), ME 37-48 (Box 3)
  - Mechanical Engineering negs 1958 (lab scenes; professor in office), ME 49-63 (Box 3)
- 4x5" safety negatives
  - Alumni events 1947 party scenes, 40549 (Box 4)
  - Alumni events 1947 party scenes, Palace 1-6 (Box 4)
  - Class of 1942 members at 1947 alumni events, 42-1 – 42-4 (Box 4)
  - Class of 1937 members at 1947 alumni events, 37-1 – 37-6 (Box 4)
  - Big Game Rally 1947? (R. L. Wilbur & Sterling at microphone) (Box 4)
  - Big Game Rally 1947? (crowd on bleachers) (Box 4)
  - Big Game Rally 1947? (crowd on bleachers) (Box 4)
  - Alumni Events 1948 party scenes, 48-1 – 48-18 (Box 4)
  - Hammer and Coffin 50th Anniversary Banquet 1949, 40566 (Box 4)
  - Alumni events 1949 party scenes [slightly warped negatives], 49-1 – 49-16 (Box 5)
  - Alumni events 1953 party scenes, 53-1 – 53-19 (Box 5)
  - Alumni events 1954 party scenes, 54-1 – 54-15 (Box 5)
- 4x5" safety negatives and color transparencies
  - Alumni events 1955 party scenes, 55-1 – 55-13 (Box 6)
  - S.U. Band parading on S. F. streets 1955, 55-14 – 55-15 (Box 6)
  - Alumni events 1955 party scenes, 55-16 – 55-25 (Box 6)
  - Dr. Hans Barkan (4 negatives and 4 proofs) (Box 6)
  - S. F. 49ers (5 men) at Stanford Sept. 21, 1948 (2 negatives) (Box 6)
  - Carol Green Wilson at Stanford Women's Club of San Francisco, n.d. (3 negatives) (Box 6)
  - Stanford Alumni X Committee, May 21, 1950 (2 negatives) (Box 6)
  - Front of Library (2 color transparencies) (Box 6)
  - Engineering corner (1 color transparency) (Box 6)
  - History corner (1 color transparency) (Box 6)
Index to Negatives
1 Men's dorm or fraternity: sitting in lounge and guy washing dishes
2 At the Press: people working with type and on typewriters, etc.
3 At the Press: people at their desks, one man dealing with photographs
4 Campus firemen at the old firehouse
5 Hashers in dorm
6 At the Press (same people as in rolls 2 and 3)
7 ROTC color guard
8 Men's dorm or fraternity (same lounge as in Roll 1); half the images are quite dark
10 Hashers in dorm
11 Radio studio; men in dorm room
12 Campus firemen
13 Men in dorm rooms; group meeting (?)
14 Campus firemen
201 Lecture class and students at microscopes; possibly medical students (everyone in white lab coats)
202 Class in large lecture hall, possibly a law class; very few women students
283 Class scenes, possibly physics or engineering
309 Medical class (nurses and doctors)
311 Possibly a medical class (everyone is wearing white lab coats)
314 Art class (painting)
334 Class (all male students); two images of professor at chalk board
445 Class or lab scenes, students using microscopes, looking at animal skeletons
CC Images of Dr. J. R. Miller and another doctor at work; both seem to be pediatricians
C30 Classroom scenes, men and women students [not a Quad classroom]
C48 Chemistry class (lab)
EE Possibly an electrical engineering lab (male students with equipment)
S Images of one person (probably a doctor or intern) looking at slides, x-rays, and using a microscope
W medical students and/or interns